A: Sfax, Tunisia

MY PROFILE

Passionate, hard worker, motivated and tenacious with over 2 years of experience in Software Engineering as a Full Stack Developer. Highly skilled in coding with any language I can learn. I can either work alone or within a team. I can easy communicate with team members. I graduated with a Software Engineer Degree.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer - Byrsa-Tech (Sfax, Tunisia)

Dec 2021 - Now

- Website Development for real-estate management with high functionalities to facilitate the customer to get offers
 from the agents with high searching terms. Worked on it alone with my manager for reviews using Spring Boot Java
 with SSR (Single-Responsibility Principle) and Quasar Framework (VueJs) for front end alongside Pinia for state
 management.
- Build an OAuth authorization server using Spring Authorization Server to secure the API of multiple applications and the legibility to connect and login to the Server.
- Web and Mobile application for the government to help civil servant and public servant either for shopping, booking including some coupons with a high secured system including the Pro Interface for the administration. Encrypting data to secure all the confidential data related to the user. I participated mostly for Backend functionalities and the linking between the project and the Authorization Server.

Full Stack Developer - DSO Services | Graduation Project (Sfax, Tunisia)

Fev 2021 - Oct 2021

- Website/Mobile Development as PaaS called Timesheet. A platform for companies to manage timesheet reports for its users. The application was developed using Angular, Ionic and Spring Boot.
- The application includes five types of user:
 - Consultant: The user can fill his timesheet in a table and send and email and a notification to his manager to validate it. He has also the possibility to print his report after being signed as a PDF including both E-Signatures.
 - Manager: He can validate and manage (CRUD) consultants and clients and holidays (depends on each client's country using Google Calendar API). And the number of consultants and clients depends on the credits which can be purchased (Stripe SDK)
 - Client: He can view the consultants reports and sign them.
 - Admin: He can manage everything related to his company.
 - Super Admin: He can manager everything in the system including every company's data.

TRAINING - INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer - SiFAST (Sfax, Tunisia)

Jul 2020 - Aug 2020

- The project is to build a website to generate Kubernetes files to make it easier for the developer. Instead of writing all the YAML files manually, he can just use the website with an easy UI to generate all the complicated things including all the details he wants.
- The project was developed using Symfony 4 with Sonata and was deployed by Docker to manage all the data and the databases.
- Added more features and fixed many bugs to make the system more clear and the eligibility to download a zip file contains all the YAML files ordered.

- Charity mobile application during the Covid-19 for our region Sfax especially for the students. The main goal of the application to let the user either get help or donate anything to help others in need. I used Flutter for front-end development and Firebase for backend to make the service works as soon as possible.
- The application has two type of users
 - Normal User: He can login to the application and share his location. He can check the list of needs of all other students and if he can donate a specify things through the list of items, he will just make a request of donation. Otherwise, he can make a request of help of anything he wants to donate.
 - Delivery User: He can check all the donations/needs requests with all the details including the items, food or products and the location of the user. And when he finish delivering the items, he can check it to make it done. He can filter all the donations lists to know which item more donated or needed.

Game Developer - Turku University of Applied Sciences (Turku, Finland)

Feb 2018 - Apr 2018

- Mobile/Game Application for a virtual visit of Bardo Museum.
- The user can check details and history of Bardo through a dictionary. And he can use his voice using Speech To Text from IBM to search instead of typing.
- For the virtual reality, the user can enter inside two rooms and check all the paintings inside the Museum and unlock them to check their details.
- The game was made by the collaboration between the two teams of the university

Game Developer - Mediterranean Development Initiative (Sfax, Tunisia)

Jul 2017 - Aug 2017

- Mobile game 2D, Arcade, funny and one tap called Draw A Way
- The main concept of the game: there is a ball falling down. The player shouldn't let the ball fall down or touch any obstacle. He can draw lines to prevent the ball from touching or falling. Including super powers.
- The player can purchase skins for the ball or the background of the game and also super powers.
- Roulette to let the player win a random gift from the game (free spin daily)
- Push Notification (can also a gift) using OneSignal SDK

EDUCATION

Software Engineer Degree

International Institute of Technology | Sfax, Tunisia

July 2021

• Studied Software, Website and mobile development. Also, database administration, ERP, UML, design patterns, data warehouse, Big Data and machine learning. For programming languages, I used mostly Java and Python. Fo frameworks, I used Spring Boot and sometimes Firebase for Backend and Angular for Front-end.

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science and Multimedia.

Higher Institute of Computer Science and Multimedia of Sfax | Sfax, Tunisia

July 2018

Studied basics of Computer Science, few programming languages starting from the language C and Java, UML,
 Game Development and Website Development using basics HTML/CSS/JS.

QUALIFICATIONS

- C# Software Development Fundamental (Microsoft)
- Big Data Engineer IBM
- Introduction to Programming Using HTML and CSS (Microsoft)
- Fast learner and eager to learn skills
- Attention to details
- Adaptability
- Time Management
- Trilingual: Arabic (Native) French (Conversational) English (Fluent)
- Winner of many programming competitions Coach of Web Development and Game Development during clubs and competitions